<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Paulo Bonifácio</title>
    <link>https://bonif.netlify.app/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://bonif.netlify.app/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 12:39:53 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://bonif.netlify.app/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://bonif.netlify.app/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study of the present state and of recent temporal changes in the benthic macrofauna composition of Gulf of Lions soft-bottoms macrobenthic communities, NW Mediterranean</title>
      <link>https://bonif.netlify.app/project/thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 12:39:53 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bonif.netlify.app/project/thesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The main objectives of my thesis were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to assess the present state and recent (1998 vs. 2010) changes in benthic macrofauna composition of the Gulf of Lions soft-bottom communities through the long term comparison of 91 stations;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to test the current paradigm regarding the control of those communities by climatic parameters through a 10-year monitoring of 4 stations located in the Bay of Banyuls-sur-Mer;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to assess the influence of Rhône River inputs on the composition of benthic macrofauna through the sampling, of 5 stations, under 4 hydrological regimes; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to update the ecological quality status of Gulf of Lions benthic habitats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My results have shown the persistence of the same 3 communities between 1998 and 2010, the strong influence of both the NAO and the Rhône River on benthic macrofauna composition in the whole Gulf. They also showed a control of benthic macrofauna by climatic oscillations with the WeMO contributing most especially during wintertime. Moreover, the stations most impacted by Rhône River inputs were located close to its mouth. They are negatively affected during floods and positively affected during dry periods. Lastly, I have updated the sensitivity/tolerance levels of Mediterranean species and confirmed the existence of major discrepancies in the results derived from different biotic indices used, although all tested indices indicated an overall stability in the ecological quality status of benthic habitats between 1998 and 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep-sea taxonomy of polychaetes</title>
      <link>https://bonif.netlify.app/project/deeptaxonomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 12:38:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bonif.netlify.app/project/deeptaxonomy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About 90% of deep-sea polychaetes from the CCFZ are new for science (Glover et al., 2002). The main goal of this project is to describe as much as I can along next years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until now, I have described 19 species with one for coastal waters and 18 for deep-sea. 17 from the CCFZ and one from hydrothermal vents.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIDAS</title>
      <link>https://bonif.netlify.app/project/midas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bonif.netlify.app/project/midas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eu-midas.net/about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MIDAS website&lt;/a&gt;, the partnership comprises 32 organisations from across Europe, including research institutes, universities, specialist SMEs and industry partners. This partnership brings together a wealth of scientific expertise in deep-sea biology, ecology, biochemistry, oceanography, geology and geochemistry to work alongside specialists in marine policy, environmental regulation and legislation. A critical component of the partnership is the expertise in deep-sea exploitation operations and technologies brought by our industry partners, who will also drive the engagement with other commercial stakeholders in the offshore sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MIDAS has an ambitious set of objectives, aimed at building the knowledge base to underpin sound environmental policies in relation to deep-sea exploitation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To identify the scale of possible impacts, and their duration, on deep-sea ecosystems associated with different types of resource extraction activities;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To develop workable solutions and best practice codes for environmentally sound and socially acceptable commercial activities;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To develop cost-effective technologies for monitoring the impacts of mineral exploitation and the subsequent recovery of ecosystems;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To work with policy makers in the European and international arenas to enshrine best practice in international and national regulations and overarching legal frameworks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JPI Oceans project &#39;MiningImpact&#39; </title>
      <link>https://bonif.netlify.app/project/jpio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bonif.netlify.app/project/jpio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According the framework of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jpi-oceans.eu/miningimpact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;JPI Oceans action &amp;lsquo;Ecological aspects of deep-sea mining&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt;, the project &amp;lsquo;MiningImpact&amp;rsquo; aimed to assess the long-term impacts of polymetallic nodule mining on the deep-sea environment. Core of the project were three marine research campaigns conducted in 2015 on the RV Sonne visiting several license areas and two Areas of Particular Environmental Interest (APEIs) in the Clarion-Clipperton Fracture Zone (CCFZ) as well as the DISCOL benthic impact experiment in the Peru Basin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jointly analyse the long-term ecological consequences of deep-sea polymetallic nodule mining to provide the knowledge base and inform the development of the international regulation regime of deep sea mining activities by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Predicting the ecological, biogeochemical and hydrodynamic consequences of a mining impact;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testing a range of modern rapid assessment methods and monitoring techniques for defining the ecosystem status;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicating the results to stakeholders and policymakers;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conducting a comparative baseline study across different deep-sea environments (e.g. trophic states and seamounts)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
