<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mining | Paulo Bonifácio</title>
    <link>https://bonif.netlify.app/tag/mining/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://bonif.netlify.app/tag/mining/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Mining</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://bonif.netlify.app/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Mining</title>
      <link>https://bonif.netlify.app/tag/mining/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alpha and beta diversity patterns of polychaete assemblages across the nodule province of the eastern Clarion-Clipperton Fracture Zone (equatorial Pacific)</title>
      <link>https://bonif.netlify.app/publication/bonifacioetal2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bonif.netlify.app/publication/bonifacioetal2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SEDIMENT MACROFAUNA – A synthesis of sediment macrofaunal biodiversity in the Clarion-Clipperton Zone</title>
      <link>https://bonif.netlify.app/publication/smith-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bonif.netlify.app/publication/smith-uk/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New genera and species from the Equatorial Pacific provide phylogenetic insights into deep-sea Polynoidae (Annelida)</title>
      <link>https://bonif.netlify.app/publication/bonifacio-2018-ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bonif.netlify.app/publication/bonifacio-2018-ed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;i class=&#34;fab fa-r-project  pr-1 fa-fw&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; R&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Community Structure of Deep-Sea Macrofauna Associated with Polymetallic Nodules in the Eastern Part of the Clarion-Clipperton Fracture Zone</title>
      <link>https://bonif.netlify.app/publication/de-smet-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bonif.netlify.app/publication/de-smet-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The London Workshop on the Biogeography and Connectivity of the Clarion-Clipperton Zone</title>
      <link>https://bonif.netlify.app/publication/glover-2016-ey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bonif.netlify.app/publication/glover-2016-ey/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIDAS</title>
      <link>https://bonif.netlify.app/project/midas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bonif.netlify.app/project/midas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eu-midas.net/about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MIDAS website&lt;/a&gt;, the partnership comprises 32 organisations from across Europe, including research institutes, universities, specialist SMEs and industry partners. This partnership brings together a wealth of scientific expertise in deep-sea biology, ecology, biochemistry, oceanography, geology and geochemistry to work alongside specialists in marine policy, environmental regulation and legislation. A critical component of the partnership is the expertise in deep-sea exploitation operations and technologies brought by our industry partners, who will also drive the engagement with other commercial stakeholders in the offshore sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MIDAS has an ambitious set of objectives, aimed at building the knowledge base to underpin sound environmental policies in relation to deep-sea exploitation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To identify the scale of possible impacts, and their duration, on deep-sea ecosystems associated with different types of resource extraction activities;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To develop workable solutions and best practice codes for environmentally sound and socially acceptable commercial activities;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To develop cost-effective technologies for monitoring the impacts of mineral exploitation and the subsequent recovery of ecosystems;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To work with policy makers in the European and international arenas to enshrine best practice in international and national regulations and overarching legal frameworks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JPI Oceans project &#39;MiningImpact&#39; </title>
      <link>https://bonif.netlify.app/project/jpio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bonif.netlify.app/project/jpio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According the framework of the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jpi-oceans.eu/miningimpact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;JPI Oceans action &amp;lsquo;Ecological aspects of deep-sea mining&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt;, the project &amp;lsquo;MiningImpact&amp;rsquo; aimed to assess the long-term impacts of polymetallic nodule mining on the deep-sea environment. Core of the project were three marine research campaigns conducted in 2015 on the RV Sonne visiting several license areas and two Areas of Particular Environmental Interest (APEIs) in the Clarion-Clipperton Fracture Zone (CCFZ) as well as the DISCOL benthic impact experiment in the Peru Basin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jointly analyse the long-term ecological consequences of deep-sea polymetallic nodule mining to provide the knowledge base and inform the development of the international regulation regime of deep sea mining activities by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Predicting the ecological, biogeochemical and hydrodynamic consequences of a mining impact;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testing a range of modern rapid assessment methods and monitoring techniques for defining the ecosystem status;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicating the results to stakeholders and policymakers;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conducting a comparative baseline study across different deep-sea environments (e.g. trophic states and seamounts)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
